Guide to the Basketball Records, 1906-[ongoing]
Duke University. University Archives
Basketball records 1906-[ongoing]
Duke University. University Archives
Duke University. Sports Information Office.
82.9 linear feet Extent: about 63,400 Items
The Sports Information Office provides information on Duke athletes and sports teams to the media. The collection includes largely clippings, statistics, press releases, programs and some correspondence. A good portion of the material is xeroxed.
UA.13.02.0002
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Boxes 43-81 (General Material) are in off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Basketball Records were received by the University Archives as transfers over time.
Historical Note
The Sports Information Office provides information about Duke athletics to the media. They also facilitate press interviews with Duke athletes and coaches. For many years, the SI Office has maintained records, photographs and other material about Duke athletic teams.
Collection Overview
The basketball records largely include clippings, statistics, press releases and programs about the Duke men's basketball team. There is some correspondence as well. A lot of the material has been xeroxed. The records range in date from 1906-ongoing.
The collection is arranged into two series: General Material, 1906-2003 and Game and Tournament Programs, 1936-2003. Due to multiple accessions, the boxes are not in sequential order and boxes 43-81 are stored offsite. For general basketball statistics, please refer to the website GoDuke.com
Subject Headings
Duke University. Sports Information Office; Duke University -- Basketball -- History -- 20th century; Duke University -- Sports
Related Material
Non-Revenue Sports Records.
Duke University Archives.
Football Records.
Duke University Archives.
Scrapbooks.
Duke University Archives.
Athletic Dept. Records.
Duke University Archives.
Photograph Collection.
Duke University Archives.
Photographic Negative Collection.
Duke University Archives.
Chanticleer Photograph Collection.
Duke University Archives.
Edmund M. Cameron Records.
Duke University Archives.
Athletics Reference Collection.
Duke University Archives.
Athletic Council Records.
Duke University Archives.
Athletics Department Football and Basketball Game Film and Video Collection
http://library.duke.edu/uarchives/holdings/film/sportsfilms.html
Contents of Collection
- General Material, 1906-2003
  - 1906 (Box 1)
  - 1932-1933 (Box 1)
  - 1933-1935 (Box 1)
  - 1934 (Box 1)
  - 1935 (Box 1)
  - 1936 (Box 1)
  - 1937 (Box 1)
  - 1938 (Box 1)
  - 1939 (Box 1)
  - 1939 (Box 1)
  - 1940 (Box 1)
  - 1940 (Box 1)
  - Stadium Opening, 1940 (Box 1)
  - 1941 (Box 1)
  - 1941 (Box 1)
  - 1941-1942 (Box 1)
  - 1941-1942 (Box 2)
  - 1942-1943 (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - 1943-1944 (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - 1944-1945 (Box 2)
  - 1945-1946 (Box 2)
  - 1946-1947 (3 folders) (Box 2)
  - 1947 (Box 2)
  - 1947-1948 (3 folders) (Box 3)
  - 1948 (Box 3)
  - 1948 (Box 3)
  - 1948-1949 (4 folders) (Box 3)
  - 1949 (Box 3)
  - 1949-1950 (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Dixie Classic, 1950 (Box 4)
  - Dick Groat, 1950-1951 (Box 4)
  - 1950-1951 (3 folders) (Box 4)
  - 1951-1952 (3 folders) (Box 4)
  - 1952-1953 (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - 1953-1954 (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - 1954-1955 (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - 1955-1956 (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - 1956-1957 (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - 1957-1958 (Box 5)
  - 1957-1958 (Box 6)
  - 1958-1959 (3 folders) (Box 6)
  - 1959-1960 (4 folders) (Box 6)
  - 1960-1961 (2 folders) (Box 6)
  - 1960-1961 (4 folders) (Box 7)
  - 1961-1962 (7 folders) (Box 7)
  - 1962-1963 (8 folders) (Box 8)
  - 1963-1964 (2 folders) (Box 8)
  - 1963-1964 (8 folders) (Box 9)
  - 1964-1965 (7 folders) (Box 10)
  - 1965-1966 (8 folders) (Box 10)
  - 1966-1967 (7 folders) (Box 11)
  - 1967-1968 (7 folders) (Box 11)
  - 1967-1968 (Box 12)
  - 1968-1969 (7 folders) (Box 12)
  - 1969-1970 (3 folders) (Box 12)
  - 1969-1970 (5 folders) (Box 13)
  - 1970-1971 (5 folders) (Box 13)
  - 1971-1972 (3 folders) (Box 13)
  - 1971-1972 (2 folders) (Box 14)
  - 1972-1973 (5 folders) (Box 14)
  - 1973-1974 (4 folders) (Box 14)
  - 1974-1975 (2 folders) (Box 14)
  - 1974-1975 (2 folders) (Box 15)
  - 1975-1976 (5 folders) (Box 15)
  - 1976-1977 (5 folders) (Box 15)
  - 1977-1978 (3 folders) (Box 15)
  - 1977-1978 (5 folders) (Box 16)
  - 1978-1979 (5 folders) (Box 16)
  - 1978-1979 (Box 17)
  - 1979-1980 (9 folders) (Box 17)
  - 1980-1982 (Box 43)
  - 1982-1983 (Box 44)
  - 1983-1985 (Box 45)
  - 1984-1986 (Box 46)
  - 1985-1987 (Box 47)
  - 1987-1988 (Box 48)
  - 1987-1989 (Box 49)
  - 1988-1989 (Box 50)
  - 1989-1990 (Box 51)
  - 1989-1990 (Box 52)
  - 1990-1991 (Box 53)
  - 1990-1991 (Box 54)
  - 1990-1992 (Box 55)
  - 1991-1992 (Box 56)
  - 1991-1993 (Box 57)
  - 1992-1994 (Box 58)
  - 1993-1994 (Box 59)
  - 1994-1995 (Box 60)
  - 1994-1995 (Box 61)
  - 1995-1997 (Box 62)
  - 1995-1997 (Box 63)
  - 1996-1997 (Box 64)
  - 1996-1997 (Box 65)
  - 1997-1998 (Box 66)
  - 1997-1998 (Box 67)
  - 1997-1998 (Box 68)
  - 1998-1999 (Box 69)
  - 1998-1999 (Box 70)
  - 1998-1999 (Box 71)
  - 1998-2000 (Box 72)
  - 1999-2000 (Box 73)
  - 2000-2001 (Box 74)
  - 2000-2001 (Box 75)
  - 2000-2002 (Box 76)
  - 2001-2002 (Box 77)
  - 2001-2002 (Box 78)
  - 2002-2003 (Box 79)
  - 2002-2003 (Box 80)
  - 2002-2003 (Box 81)
  - Radio Broadcasts, Casette Tapes, Spring 1985 (Box 82)
- Game and Tournament Programs, 1936-2003
  - 1936-1967 (Box 18)
  - 1968-1972 (Box 19)
  - 1973-Feb 1977 (Box 20)
  - Nov 1977-Mar 1981 (Box 21)
  - Mar 1981-Mar 1984 (Box 22)
  - Nov 1984-Dec 1986 (Box 23)
  - Dec 1986-Mar 1988 (Box 24)
  - Mar 1988-Dec 1989 (Box 25)
  - Jan 1990-Dec 1990 (Box 26)
  - Dec 1990-Mar 1991 (Box 27)
  - Apr 1991-Feb 1992 (Box 28)
  - Feb 1992-Jan 1993 (Box 29)
  - Jan 1993-Feb 1994 (Box 30)
  - Feb 1994-Dec 1994 (Box 31)
  - Dec 1994-Mar 1995 (Box 32)
  - Nov 1995-Feb 1996 (Box 33)
  - Mar 1996-Feb 1997 (Box 34)
  - Feb 1997-Jan 1998 (Box 35)
  - Jan 1998-Nov 1998 (Box 36)
  - Dec 1998-Feb 1999 (Box 37)
  - Mar 1999-Jan 2000 (Box 38)
  - Feb 2000-Apr 2001 (Box 39)
  - Nov 2001-Feb 2002 (Box 40)
  - Mar 2002-Feb 2003 (Box 41)
  - Feb 2003-Mar 2003 (Box 42)
- Duke Basketball [serial] 1951-ongoing
  Variant titles include Duke basketball press guide, Duke basketball media guide, Duke basketball magazine, Duke basketball yearbook. This serial has been cataloged individually (call number GV885.72.D87 D854) and is located onsite with other basketball records.
  - 1951-1987 (missing 1959/60 and 1962/63) (Box 1)
  - 1987-1994 (Box 2)
  - 1994-1999 (Box 3)
  - 1999-2008 (Box 4)
  - 2009- (Box 7)
  - copy 2, 1989/90-1999/00 (Box 5)
  - copy 2, 1951/52-1988/89 (Box 6)